# **Kristy Hamlin**

# **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Miami, FL 33156 | Kristy.hamlin12@gmail.com | 305-394-0655 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/kristyhamlin/

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Top-achieving **Software Engineering Graduate** with experience in Java, Python, Software Design, and Scrum Methodology. Bringing 9 years of professional experience in scientific research and positioned to thrive in software development environments where strong collaboration skills, writing, and problem-solving skills are key. Known for being a team-player and culture-setter.

#### Skills/Software:

- Java, Python, C, HTML, CSS
- Object-Oriented Design, Data Structures and Algorithms
- Microsoft Power Apps, Power Automate
- Machine Learning, Al
- Git, Github, Version Control

- Software Testing, Unit Testing, System Testing
- Relational Database Design, SQL, Query optimization
- UX, Human-Computer Interaction
- Agile Development, SCRUM

# **SELECTED CODING PROJECTS**

# Microsoft Power Apps: Enhancing FIU's STARS Tutoring Administration

Served as Team Leader | Mentor & Product Owner: Dr. Patricia Wells

Designed, tested, and developed a system in Microsoft Power Apps to provide process automation for FIU's "STARS" Tutoring service, currently administered manually by Dr. Patricia Wells.

- Reviewed system requirements and business processes from Product Owner and refined them into actionable use cases and user stories. Implemented optimized workflows using Power Apps.
- Wrote comprehensive documentation for stakeholders, effectively communicating the system design and illustrating relationships between workflows and data sources.
- Simplified the Excel-based data management of the system, reducing redundant workflows to about 1/4, greatly enhancing maintainability and scalability.

#### **Portfolio Site**

Individual Project | https://kristy-nicole.github.io/kh-portfolio-website/

Designed and developed a user-friendly, attractive portfolio site to showcase materials from my software engineering projects and science career.

### **Predicting Miami Housing Prices using Machine Learning**

Individual Project | Introduction to Machine Learning

Utilized Python's Pandas and Sklearn libraries to implement a model to predict Miami Housing Prices, using a Kaggle dataset with 14,000 objects.

• Achieved a MAE of \$52,000 and R-squared of 0.78 using a Decision Tree Regressor.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

BioTissue | Miami, FL

08/2018 - Ongoing

https://biotissue.com/

Lab Supervisor (07/2022 – Present)

 Promoted to R&D Lab Supervisor in 2022 after excelling at the Research Associate position – demonstrating loyalty, growth, and initiative. KRISTY HAMLIN PAGE 2

• Led team of scientists to ensure on-time production of qualified samples to partner studies at Johns Hopkins University consistently for over 2 years.

- Communicate project statuses for team at weekly departmental meeting.
- Spearheaded research project to optimize the Western Blot Assay, successfully resolving multiple key problems encountered by scientists. Generated technical documentation on the experiments performed, data, and results.
- Led departmental "Great Place to Work" initiative, resulting in R&D survey ratings of the GPTW statement rising from 67% to 83% in 2023, fostering a positive work environment.

## Research Associate (08/2018 – 07/2022)

- Followed Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs) to perform lab research experiments
- Generated data, analyzed data, and wrote technical reports for company research projects
- Effective and experienced in a hybrid and remote work environment. Able to work unsupervised.

# **EDUCATION**

Florida International University | Miami, FL
BS in Computer Science, Software Development Track
University of Miami | Miami, FL
BS in BioChemistry, BA in English Literature

Kristy Hamlin 8255 Sw 98<sup>th</sup> Street Miami FL, 33156 305 394 0655 Kristy.hamlin12@gmail.com

Hiring Manager for "Software Engineer – Technology Development Program" Dick's Sporting Goods

October 9, 2024

To Whom it May Concern,

I am thrilled to apply for the Software Engineering Technology Development Program at Dick's Sporting Goods, and about the opportunity to both further my software skills in a professional environment as well as contribute to DSG's mission to offer top-quality sporting and outdoors equipment to athletes and enthusiasts. I do not normally share this in job applications, but afterhours I am a competitive dancer and avid mountain-biker, and I love going to Dick's.

I am a motivated and top-performing recent graduate with a Bachelor's in Computer Science from Florida International University. I have a 9 years of professional experience in Biochemistry, but it is my goal to transition to Software Development, a field I have found deeply interesting and rewarding during my studies. Although I am new to software, I have a proven track record of being an engaged, loyal, and driven professional at work.

Highlights of my application include the following:

- I have worked on various complex coding projects and demonstrated my ability to quickly learn new programming concepts and effectively apply them to solve challenging problems
- I am highly motivated and complete self-learning on an ongoing basis. I frequently outperformed more experienced developers thanks to my strong worth ethic and persistence.
- My professional background in science gives me key strengths including already-polished soft-skills for a corporate environment.

You may speak directly with my current colleagues and superiors regarding my performance and commitment to excellence. I believe they will tell you that I am a considerate team member, as well as reliable and motivated. I am truly looking for my next home, and a place where I can grow and contribute.

Although I did not have any software internships – as I could not give up my fulltime job during my studies – I believe my work experience and tenacity makes me a top candidate. Please reach out to me via phone or email if my application catches your eye, as I sincerely hope it does,

Kristy Hamlin

Kristy.hamlin12@gmail.com | 305 394 0655 | www.linkedin.com/in/kristyhamlin